thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of iceland
for q3 2021 and for 9 months 2021
uh hope all of you and your colleagues
are staying safe and healthy
so what i'll do is i'll give a brief
overview of the industry trends
and developments that we've witnessed uh
in the you know
past few months post this our cfo gopala
children will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and nine months ended december
2020.
the growth trajectory seen in the
economy since the second quarter of 2021
has picked up in this quarter
uh the high frequency indicators like
automobile sales uh
railway freight traffic growth in
non-oil and non-gold imports seen during
third quarter shows
hopeful sign that of a sharper recovery
than what we
anticipate at the beginning of the year
in fact some of the worsted sectors such
as
hospitality and travel have also seen
some pick up in the third quarter
and the introduction of the vaccine is
expected to catalyze
economic activities further which can
provide tailwinds
for india's economic growth now in this
context
the general insurance industry has been
a safe harbor even through the times
of uncertainty with across direct
premium income
back in the black segments such as the
motor insurance
saw encouraging performance during this
quarter uh driven by growing need for
personal
mobility and spillover demand from the
festive seasons
the pent up demand for health insurance
seen in the first half has
shown some signs of tapering as far as
commercial lines are concerned the fire
segment continued to show rover's growth
aided by the rate hike that came into
force in january 2020
while marine and engineering lines
witness some pickup with the resumption
of
economic activity in this quarter with
the current macro and micro
integrators indicators coming to play we
remain confident that the gi industry is
set to outperform that in terms of
growth
now speaking of the performance as per
the disclosure on the website of idi the
general insurance
industry registered a growth of 2.5
percent for nine months
2021 over the previous nine months
with the industry gdpi moving up to uh
one
uh one four five six point seven nine
billion uh in nine month twenty twenty
one from one four two zero point eight
five billion rupees in nine month twenty
twenty two twenty twenty
the combined ratio for the industry was
hundred 105.2 in the first half of 2021
as compared to 115.7
in the first half of 2020 based on
available information from public
disclosures
excluding one company which has not
disclosed its numbers for q2fa 2021 as
yet
further the overall combined ratio for
the private multi-line general insurance
was
insurers was 103.0 in h1 2021
as compared to 107.2 in h1 2020.
now since our half yearly results call
we have witnessed new regulatory
announcements that are focused on
policyholders benefit
including the exposure draft with
standard terms and conditions issued by
the authority
in order to make available standard
travel insurance personal
accident and named indemnity-based
vector-borne products with common
coverage and policy wording across the
industry
the authority also issued guidelines on
certain standard products that shall be
mandatory
offered by general insurance insurance
carrying out fire and allied perils
insurance business with effect from
first
april 2020. the standard products
include
bharat grihar raksha meant for home
building and home content
bharatiyam suraksha meant for enterprise
with total value at risk up to rupees
five crores
and bharat lagoon suraksha meant for
enterprises
with total value at risk from five
crores to twenty five crews
the authority had also issued an
exposure draft on withdrawal of existing
long-term credit link group insurance
products
under the health insurance business with
effect from january 1 2021
the industry through the gi council had
represent has represented the industry
let me now turn to the claims behavior
observed in the recent quarters
with the economic activity normalizing
post motorola claim
you know normalizing motor od claim
frequency has reached previous levels
in case of health overall claim
frequency has almost reached pre-covered
levels
for the industry covert claims covet
claims reported as on december 31 2020
was
roughly about 7.68 lakhs of its 39 000
claims were reported with
isis in lombard however the new covet
cases reported in the month of december
has seen slight moderation
the recent pandemic provided us an
opportunity to foster an accelerated
innovation
deliver improved customer service
upskilling and reskilling of our
employees and distributors
over 97.5 policies 97.5
percent policies issued by us in the
nine month end of december 2020 where
our input paper is formed
under the sme segment close to 91 of the
business sourced worked through these
digital solutions
during the quarter we also launched a
website dedicated for our
small and medium businesses the new
platform will serve as a one-stop
solution for sme owners to buy
or renew insurance products endorse
their insurance policies and register
claims
this is first in the industry in our
previous call we
also shared about our new technology uh
technology
enabled enablements including the ai and
ml solutions
that help in policy issues claims and
fraud control and servicing
our automated ai solution auto you know
auto approved close to uh 66 percent of
motor braking and self inspections in
december 2020
up from 40.6 in march 2020. on the
health insurance front
under group health policies three point
one percent of the fresh cashless
requests
were authorized by an aiml enabled
engine for december 2020
as compared to thirty one percent in
march uh 2020.
our mobile app uh i'll take care has
crossed three point four four lakh
downloads
enabling more and more customers to
avail our insurance and wellness
solutions
we continue to add digital capabilities
and servicing including the process of
endorsements
since its launch last year 73 of all
group help
premium bearing endorsements are now
done digitally reducing processing time
from weeks to minutes
and roughly about 45 percent of our
motor policy endorsements
from agency channel are processed real
time using our digital solutions
we've also in introduce a revised hr
policy wherein
employees can work from anywhere even
post the pandemic while ensuring work
environment we create is comfortable and
secure
now through this unprecedented year our
laser focus has been on enhancing
customer experience
new product offerings creating workplace
transformation thereby adding value to
our stakeholders
we are continually focusing on in
evolving our strategies to further
consolidate our position in general
engine segment
while retaining our mission of creating
long-term values for our
stakeholders through prudent risk
election and sustained profitability
i will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter
uh thanks bhagav and uh good evening to
each one of you
i will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for quarter three this year
and nine months this year we have put up
the results presentation on our website
you can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers
the gross direct premium income of the
company stood at rupees 105.25 billion
in nine months
fy21 as compared to 101.32 billion in
nine months last year
a growth of 3.9 percent compared to
industry growth of 2.5 percent
for a similar period on a quarterly
basis the gdp grew in quarter three by
nine point two percent
over quarter three last year compared to
the industry growth of four point nine
percent
our focus on preferred segments
primarily draw a gdpi growth
consequent to the increase in minimum
prescribed rates for certain occupancies
under the fire segment
this portfolio registered a robust gdpa
growth of 44.8 percent in nine months
fy21
thereby catalyzing the gdp growth of our
property and casualty segment
going forward the growth in this segment
is expected to normalize
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall property and casualty
segment
grew by 22 percent for nine months fy 21
over nine months fi 2020 on the retail
side of the business
motor segment was back in the black
registering a growth of two point one
percent in nine months fi twenty one
individual health indemnity business
grew by twenty five point seven percent
for nine month fi 2021.
to harness the potential of these
segments we have been expanding our
distribution network
to increase penetration entire three
entire four cities our agents
including the point of sale distribution
or pause increase to 55
615 as on december 31 2020
up from 52 785 as on september 30 2020.
the advanced premium numbers was rupees
31.97 billion
as at december 31 2020 from
31.60 billion as at september 30 2020.
in so far as the progress in relation to
the scheme of arrangement with bharti
exa is concerned
we have filed the application with nclt
and nclt has directed us to convene a
meeting of shareholders
to consider and approve the scheme of
arrangement on february 23 2021.
the expenses incurred of about 0.36
billion
have been absorbed in the p l during
nine months fy 2021.
our combined ratio stood at 99.1 percent
in nine months fi 2021
compared to 100.5 percent in nine months
fbi 2020
despite the cyclone and flood losses
excluding the impact of cyclone and
flood losses the combined ratio stood at
97.7 percent in
nine months fi 2021 as against 99.5
in nine months fy 2020 combined ratio
for the quarter three stood at 97.9
compared to 98.7 percent in quarter
three last year
excluding the impact of cyclone and
floods for the quarter three the
combined ratio stood at 96.6 percent in
this quarter
as against 98.7 percent in quarter three
fy 2020
our investment assets rose to 298.92
billion at december 31 2020
as compared to 291.62 billion at
september 30 2020.
our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.05 times at december 31
2020 as compared
to 4.13 times at september 30 2020.
investment income increased to 16.59
billion in nine months fi 21
as compared to 14.41 billion in nine
months fbi 2020.
on a quarterly basis investment income
increased to five point six eight
billion rupees in quarter three five
twenty one
as compared to four point two seven
billion in quarter three up by twenty
twenty
within this our capital gains was at
rupees two point nine two billion in
nine months five twenty one
as compared to two point two four
billions in nine months fbi 2020
capital gains for quarter three five
twenty one was at rupees 1.08 billion
as compared to rupees point one seven
billion in quarter three of by 2020
our profit before tracks grew by
thirteen point four percent to rupees
fifteen point zero four billion in nine
months five twenty one
as compared to rupees thirteen point two
six billion in nine months fi twenty
twenty
whereas profit before tax grew by seven
point three percent to four point one
eight billion in quarter three or five
twenty one
as compared to rupees three point nine
zero billion in quarter three five
twenty
this includes upfront expensing of
acquisition cost
relative to the growth of nine point two
percent in gdp for quarter three five
twenty
twenty twenty 2021 whereas the full
benefit of the earned premium will be
realized over the
policy period consequently profit after
tax grew by twenty three point six
percent to rupees 11.27 billion in nine
months fi 21
as compared to rupees nine point one two
billion in nine months fy 2020
primarily due to lower effective tax
rate of 25 percent
profit after tax grew by 6.6 percent to
3.14 billion in quarter three fi 21
as compared to rupees 2.94 billion in
quarter three of by
twenty written on average equity was
twenty two point four percent in nine
months five twenty one
as compared to twenty one point eight
percent in nine months at five twenty
the return on average equity for quarter
three five twenty one was seventeen
point six percent
as compared to twenty point three
percent in quarter three fi twenty
twenty
this includes the upfront expensing or
acquisition cost which i referred to
earlier
relative to the growth of nine point two
percent gdp for quarter three five
twenty twenty one
whereas the full benefit of earned
premium will be realized over the policy
period
solvency ratio was 2.76 times at
december 31 2020
as against 2.74 times at september 30
continued to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.5
as i conclude i would like to reiterate
that we ended quarter 3 and 9 months
with healthy financials
our competitive strengths which
contribute to sustainability
and positions as well for future growth
includes consistency market leadership
diversified product mix with
multi-channel distribution network
excellence in customer service and
technology robust risk selection
and strong investment returns on
diversified portfolio
through our business performance we have
always endeavored to create long-term
sustainable value for all our
stakeholders
i would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings conference call
and would be happy to take questions
that you may have thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
questioning queue you may press star and
two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
to ask questions please press star and
one
the first question is from the line of
vitae gulati from high tongue please go
ahead
yes sir thank you for giving me an
opportunity uh so my question is related
to the benefit policies that you spoke
about so can you just update us on what
is the latest
regarding what irda is saying regarding
these policies to attach along with
their loan products and also if you
could help us with how much of benefit
versus inflammation we have done in q3
and what has been the claim ratio of the
two categories
so let me uh answer the first part of
the question and i'll ask
gopal to explain the overall uh you know
numbers on the benefit side
uh this quarter visa v q3 of uh last
year
so in terms of the circular the circular
had the given
you know it was an exposure it was a you
know
kind of an exposure draft which said
that from first january onwards
these policies will be uh stopped uh as
an industry we
uh obviously represented uh you know
this would have we believe
uh you know negative impact so we
represented
uh as of now we've not heard anything
either way
but the fact is that the uh draft uh uh
you know policy hasn't been converted
into a final uh regulation
effective first january so uh as of now
it's not been withdrawn
and that is the status uh when we
finally get a confirmation we can give
you the
final picture from the regulatory
perspective
one of the things that has happened for
us in icc lombard is that
a large part of our benefit uh you know
health benefit policies is uh comes
through
bank issue and channel in any case and
within that
from icsa bank and you know
separate from this uh circular uh icc
bank had uh anyway decided
uh you know sometime in early this
quarter
that they would you know reduce the
focus of distribution of health
insurance
you know business particularly
attachment side because they are
focusing on
building out the code banking business
given that
you know the first half it was low and
you know the opportunities are high
they wanted the team to focus on code
banking business
the bank has indicated that it would
obviously re-assess this approach in due
course
uh but because of that call of the bank
anyways
you know whether the circuit is
effective or not as of now our benefit
business has come
down significantly and if you look at
our aggregate health numbers
that's one of the reasons why we've been
impacted adversely uh but specific
details about numbers i'll ask gopal to
give you
yeah i'll give you the numbers for
the retail segment because that's what
would be of uh
importance if you look at the breakup of
the retail
business that we do the indemnity
business that we did in nine months last
year was about 531 crores
this year nine months that number is
about 644 crores
a growth of about 21.3 in so far as the
benefit is concerned
the same numbers for nine months last
year was about 638 crores
that number for the nine months this
year is at about 287 crores
and to your other point with respect to
uh
what are the loss ratios that we get to
see
in so far as indemnity
is concerned is the last year again nine
months the individual loss ratios was
roughly at about 70 percent
this year uh nine months the uh
indemnity loss ratios is operating at
about 83 percent
generally it has been a profitable
segment the loss ratios kind of ranges
anywhere between i would say
uh close to 40 35 to 50 percent
depending on the experience that we see
between periods
actually the reason is because over the
last three years the combined ratio in
health has been very strong at around 90
so now that we're doing some benefit
policies uh and also even if you look at
the nine months numbers are
health insurance claims combined ratio
is also looking which is expected to go
higher will that be the trend going
forward
i think so far as the trend is concerned
i think what we have
what we have explained uh even in our
prior calls
uh uh in so far as uh the nature of the
indemnity business is concerned
uh again when you split split the now
i'm talking about indemnity in the
aggregate
when you look at the corporate part of
the business inherently they come with a
very high
loss ratio but the cost of acquisition
for that portfolio is
relative in a single digit number and in
so far as
the retail portfolio is concerned the
loss ratio tends to kind of be
relatively lower however the cost of
acquisition tends to be higher
but both the portfolios put together i
think the attempt for us has been to try
and run
the overall combined ratio at the
threshold level of about
100 percent that we have spoken about uh
in so far as the way forward is
concerned i think the attempt will be to
exactly
uh continue to do that uh in so far as
this particular period is concerned as i
said
obviously there has been an impact in so
far as the growth in the benefit segment
is concerned
but however in so far as the way forward
is concerned i think we would logically
expect some of this
benefit growth to play through and the
overall
health loss ratios is something as i
said all the combined ratio is something
that we would expect to maintain at the
threshold of uh
100 that's one the second aspect is what
i spoke about also with respect to
let's say covet claims uh what we have
seen of course clearly
that all of us can see is the
incremental number of intimation seems
to be on the decline
which is quite evident and even we have
kind of seen that particular experience
obviously one will have to wait and see
how the developments takes place so far
as quarter 4 is concerned if the current
trend continues then obviously to that
extent
the experience on the loss ratio should
get better so far as kovit claims are
concerned
but at the same time on the non-covet
cases if you recollect
in terms of what we have been speaking
over the last few quarters whenever
logically we would expect a reduction in
uh covet cases
the non-covet cases will start to come
back and in quarter three specific
we have already started to see the claim
intimations coming back to
in fact slightly higher than even three
co-wait times
so hence the mix of both the attempt
will be to answer your point i think the
attempt will be on an overall
health portfolio we would want to kind
of run the book at a combined issue of
around 100 percent
so thank you that's dr truman
thank you before we take the next
question
we'd like to inform participants that in
order that the management is able to
address questions from all participants
in the conference
please limit your questions to two per
participant should you have a follow-up
question we request you to rejoin the
queue
we take the next question from the line
of ajax frederick from bnk securities
please go ahead thanks for the
opportunity
so my question is with respect to motor
uh underwriting loss ratios
so uh sorry underwriting uh quantum
uh so track was pretty worse
versus last uh req however the loss
ratios are much better
so does this imply that we are uprooting
our question cost and therefore the
unwriting
uh profit is showing showing such a big
negative number or has there been any
change to the commission structure
uh that that's my first question second
is with respect to
the change in ibnr as a proportion of uh
total claims
that has been a pretty low number this
quarter again this is because of the
conservative assumption we have done
earlier so those are my two
uh so again i'll ask gopal to answer the
second one let me answer the first one
um so if you if you remember one of the
things that we had said
at the beginning of the year was or
after the first quarter
we had seen some benefit in terms of
frequency reductions
on the motor side but we had said that
it would be imprudent to take the full
benefit in the first quarter
because there would be you know increase
in frequency as
people come back and personal mobility
picks up and we
would prefer to even it out for the year
so that's a call that we took and i
think in hindsight that's it was a
conservative call and in hindsight that
was the right call
so when you look at the loss ratio you
have to keep that in mind
uh in terms of what's happening uh you
know and so i would
you don't so look at an annual basis
rather than just on quarterly basis
the second point is what you're saying
is absolutely right so the basic
accounting you know policy that we have
in general insurance is that
the so we don't have back as in the
sourcing cost is not
uh different over the period of the
uh you know uh policy it is upfront so
whenever in a quarter we have
a high growth relative to the prior
quarters
because the income or the earning of the
policies that were written in the prior
quarter comes in now but the premium
that we write
is again spread over the next 12 months
but the sourcing cost if it is
significantly uh as in the percentage of
if the growth is very high then the
upfront cost becomes
uh you know comes and impacted in that
quarter a bit like what happens in
strain for life business with a shorter
duration
so that happens so if you see this
quarter our motor growth was
roughly about uh you know about 14 14.3
percent
but if you go back to our motor growth
in q1 was about 22 percent
minus uh and you know for the whole year
half year also it was negative six and a
half percent so we are seeing
tremendous growth uh in this quarter
relative to what we saw in the previous
quarter
so that has had the impact that you've
identified gopal uh on the ibm
on the second point our jokes i just
want to kind of get the clarity are you
referring to within the context of motor
are you
or are you referring in the context of
overall
overall override so overall obviously i
think there it is obviously
and overall you are looking at ibnr as a
percentage of
40 cams total claims obviously so yeah
so i think obviously what happens um
ajax is uh obviously ibn rs are
based on estimations of uh losses that
we expect on the
various segments of businesses and to
that to the extent
uh some of the portfolio claims are
actualized
then obviously a large part of this
claims will get reduced from
ibnr and logically kind of get converted
as a part of either claims paid
or to that extent it will be a part of
claims outstanding assuming if any of
them are yet to be settled
uh so that's one the second factor is in
this particular
quarter i think what has also happened
is in line with what we had mentioned
even in the earlier quarters
some of the outstanding crop receivables
the receipt of which had happened in
quarter one and quarter two
uh there has been outflow of claims uh
which has happened in quarter three so
hence to that extent also there is an
element of
both claims outstanding as well as let's
say to the extent of the ibinar that
would have carried on the
crop portfolio that would have
significantly seen a decrease
and the third factor is in so far as the
approach to reserving is concerned
there has been no change in the
reserving approach
vis-a-vis quarter three as compared to
any of the prior periods the approach
has pretty much remained the same and in
fact
when you look at the loss ratios
specifically in the context of
a motor for example you would have seen
for in
for example on own damage for quarter
three the loss ratios were uh were
actually at almost about
63 percent visibly let's say almost 59
percent that you had seen in quarter two
or for the matter of fact even third
party quarter three loss ratios are
about 65
as compared to let's say the tp loss
ratio of about 62
in quarter two so hence from an approach
or a methodology there is being no
change it is just that
some of those ibnr reserves that would
have been created in the earlier periods
they would have got actualized in terms
of
claims getting reported and paid yeah
that is very helpful sir thank you
thanks a lot for your time
thank you the next question is from the
line of ud karivala from amid capital
please go ahead
uh am i audible sir yeah
yeah uh thank you for the opportunity my
question was
on account of the in relation to the
investment
leverage now this is i guess
in this quarter it has come down uh to
4.05
so you could some color around this uh
what do you expect going forward
and and some rational behind history
so two major factors one is as gopal
explained there was
uh some of the older policies in crop
that we had written i mean you know as
you know money comes in much later
so premium had come in uh in the earlier
part of the year
and the payout of claims happened in
this quarter so there was a large amount
that went out
that was one secondly uh even in terms
of the leverage
uh you know for uh you know last year
has been for the year
gone by and even for hafili we've not
paid an interim dividend
because of the regulatory uh you know
mandate that we've got that none of no
no insurance company or no bank is
allowed to pay
a dividend so effectively normally we
would have paid out some dividends
that would have reduced the denominator
uh
but also we had the impact of the crop
claims being paid out uh
in one shot so but for this the number
would have been uh
you know in the you know 4.11 or 4.13
depending upon what number you look at
in that ballpark so so if i have
understood you correct you're saying
that because the dividends were not paid
your denominator
uh as in the pathway the earnings was
inflated
and and your numerator took a hit
because of the outflow on account of the
crossfire yeah
yeah if you look at that do this in the
context of a relative comparison with
the nine months of previous period i
think vargo's response
is in that context yeah and what cross
outflows are these when were these
written i mean sorry i missed that part
so these are crop portfolios udif that
we have written during the year 2018
some of which were outstanding with
respect to collectibility of premiums
and during this year which is 2021 as i
explained in quarter one and quarter two
we were able to realize a large part of
those outstanding premiums for the crop
business that we had underwritten in
2018 2019
and in quarter two and quarter three
quarter three largely is where we have
been able
we have been uh we have had a share of
outflow with respect to settlement of
those claims
okay and just one last bit related to
this do you
incrementally uh related to crop is
there any
large outfit still remaining or most of
it is now
our outstanding premiums is virtually as
good as uh
zero but for a very small amount of a
business that we're of roughly about 77
crores
is all that remains on the balance sheet
but otherwise all other
crop premiums that were outstanding as
as at the earlier balance sheets they
have all been received
thank you thank you so much
thank you the next question is from the
line of fresh chain from yes securities
please go ahead yeah uh thank you sir
of course there is a very basic question
on the mep
or nwp and ratio
that seems to have declined
substantially in this quarter
so what's the reason for that
you want to explain the accounting the
nap to nwp
uh is purely a function of
what kind of business that you write and
hence to that extent i think
whatever earnings that you would
whatever businesses that you were
underwritten i think they all get on a
one by three sixty five day basis
and to that extent i think it is purely
a function of
the volume of premiums that you have
underwritten but more importantly i
think when you look at
quarter three specific i'm not
necessarily referring to let's say
the nap to nw and wp ratio in fact
when you look at the nwp growth numbers
particularly for quarter three
you would see that the growth is almost
about twenty percent yeah so that was
the point that i was kind of referring
to now what effectively happens is
whenever you ride the businesses
let's say especially when the businesses
are growing and then what effectively
happens is the cost comes and hits you
upfront
whereas this nwp growth of 20 is
something that will start to get
earned over the policy period and in the
past periods
relatively if you see the nwp growth for
let's say quarter one and quarter two
more specifically quarter one as
compared to quarter two the growth in
nwp has been relatively lower because of
understandably so the volumes of
business were also not so great
and hence incremental earned premium
contribution
would be lower but as businesses have
started to pick up in terms of growth
logically you will start to see the nep
to nwp ratios going up
okay so going ahead ideally we should
start moving higher
is that the that is correct i think uh
in terms of how we
given the fact that now a lot of
activities have started to open up
uh in the context of whether it is the
commercial activities commercial lines
of businesses
and motor in specific again as parker
explained we have been able to have
a significant out performance in so far
as growth is concerned
and even on the health part of the
business while it has been a mixed bag
in terms of growth as we speak but
logically at least so far as the way
forward is concerned definitely in terms
of opportunity one sees a lot of
positivity in it
and hence assuming things start to get
much better than what we have seen over
the last nine months
definitely the nap to nwp ratio will
uh definitely look uh my positive
question was on the claims bit or the
severity of the health portfolio
especially on the retail side
and frequently we mentioned that the
number of claims back to three covered
levels
so with regards to severity how is that
standing out
and even for the sake for the same thing
on the motor motor ob
side do you think that the q4 could be
really
uh you know bad as uh really relatively
worse or competitive
so in terms of the health claims uh you
know what gopal explained is the numbers
have come back
but it's also on a larger base of
policies so if you look at our
uh non-covet frequency it's still
slightly lower than
uh you know what it was pre-pandemic
uh but it's kind of caught up mostly and
within that when we look at different
types of claims
we see the small medical management you
know this is medical management are
basically
uh let's say you have you have a stomach
ache you
go to the hospital for two days and come
back or you know just a you know it's a
fever
you can hospitalize for a couple of days
not surgery or not
uh you know an accidental uh you know
hospitalization etc
so those cases we've seen a lower
frequency still which is
similar trend what we've seen in the
past in terms of people not
going to hospitals you know unless they
really have to
so we've seen that frequency still
remain low uh
what that does is while the frequency
comes down the uh you know the surgery
cases are more expensive
so to that extent the acs goes up uh for
as a blend as a mix but if i look at
each of those
categories as in the you know aces or
average claims has increased for
medical management cases or elective
surgery cases or
uh you know or an emergency case uh
there the acs hasn't gone up
significantly it's you know normal
inflation nothing particularly high
covert claims uh you know gopal anyway
has given the numbers
that's coming down another thing
moto said it's it's on on iran there's
no uh
unusual spike in the acs
and also hi this is sanji we have
reserved this quarter four
uh sequentially as bhargavad mentioned
we have seen
uh improvement uh in the season actually
the
quarter on quarterboard both on private
killer and private car and two-wheeler
on cm number has been very reasonable
we do believe that waterfall on an
overall from a growth
perspective should remain positive
okay thank you so much thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of sanket goda from spark capital
please go ahead
thanks thanks for the opportunity uh
my question is again on the benefit
based health products which which is one
of the major reasons why we have a very
strong cost of living health
portfolio so i just want you to
understand if icc bank is going to
become
zero almost on incremental basis if they
continue to focus on
core banking products assuming that in
an attachment based in between this is
allowed by a regulator
then then uh then can it should be
assumed that uh
given in case the bank might be
contributing 90 percent of the benefit
based what would be doing
then again next year we could be seeing
a significant fall in this business
or do you think this could be
substituted by an agency bank or access
bank when bhartiya extra will come in
probably nfl
so that is my first question on benefit
based health
second second question which i had it
was with respect to motor tp
uh three things uh since uh actually uh
the people
of uh running on vehicles have
significantly gone up probably in three
queue
compared to second quarter still still
the loss ratios what we are reporting in
motor pp
at 65.5 uh or 65.7 in third quarter
uh are these numbers sustainable even
given given historically we always have
a higher number
and and this lower number is largely
because the lower claim information
which which actually is looking at and
therefore he is providing lower or or
is it is it generally because of the
reserve release from the past revealing
which is uh leading to this improvement
these are the two major questions one
small one which is how is with respect
to retail intensity seems to be new
region internationally seems to have
slowed down sharply in third quarter
at around 17 percent growth versus also
in q1 and 48 percent rate being q2 so so
i just wanted to understand the
broader trends day too yeah so the three
questions
okay so let me try to answer and gopal
you can step in and add
uh you know what you're saying so in
terms of the first question
on the credit link business uh so
obviously icc bank contributes a large
part of the credit link business for us
particularly the benefit piece
um if i look at the credit link business
in aggregate that's roughly about
last year was roughly about seven
percent of our of our business
uh as we speak for the q3 uh given the
fact that bank uh
uh took a call to focus on corporates
that's come down to shade lower than
three percent of our business so it's
been a
a pretty sharp reduction uh now what can
happen in the next uh you know year
uh so as at this point in time the bank
has clearly said that
they want to continue to focus on their
core business because
in essence they're coming out of uh you
know the slowdown in the moderators in
the past
and they're wanting to ramp up that
business
uh you know what they've told us is that
they will obviously
reassess this approach once things uh
stabilize so we are reasonably hopeful
that
this is something that we will get to
see uh
in the next year uh coming back but if
you look at just the
amount of business the bank does for us
on the benefit side relative to the
total business that we write
the bank contributes a bulk of the
benefit business
we also get a lot of benefit business
from the other
non-non-icc bank bank insurance partners
nbacs hfcs and other banks
that segment you know for this quarter
has actually seen a growth over last
year roughly
13 14 and it's beginning to pick up so
uh we are
reasonably hopeful that that segment
will now uh start picking up but of
course can't replace the bank
given the sheer size of the two uh
pieces now as i said so next year is one
is we
we are we are reasonably you know
hopeful that the bank will
you know review it's a reassess its
approach but the more important thing is
you know next year with if you had
a partner then by the way we are adding
partners last year we had a couple of
banker partners
this year we've added uh you know one
more partner which has
we believe reasonable potential and once
the integration happened whatever
happens
in terms of the bank of partners that we
will get obviously all of that will
uh you know compensate for any losses if
at all
it happens your second question was on
motor
um you see uh in motor again
i'll repeat what i said one of the
advantage one of the uh calls that we
took in the beginning of the year was
that we will
uh you know not take the full benefit in
the first quarter of the frequency
losses we will
you know reduction in frequency and you
will you know average it out
over the year and uh if you see some uh
some of the other players in the market
had a very sharp reduction in
uh you know let's say only noise ratios
in the first quarter in the first half
for us it was reasonably uh kind of
evened out
uh because we just wanted to be more
conservative and we believe as i said
that's the right approach
in terms of sourcing so it's in a sense
a kind of a even out uh you know lost
ratio that you're seeing
in terms of sourcing you know what we
see incrementally in the business that
we're writing
and as you know we have a predicted loss
issue when you write a write a business
uh we are in a sense back to the
pre-covet situation
if you remember we were saying uh you
know pre-lockdown that the motor od
business is
uh reached a level where the combine for
the industry is probably 110 because the
sourcing costs and the
loss ratios were pretty elevated because
of
you know hyper competition uh and we
were saying
if you remember q3 of last year and q4
of last year we are saying
we need to see some price increase and
we are beginning to see those
conversations
that were happening that obviously
stopped when the pandemic
lockdown happened as we speak today we
are in the same
boat in the sense that you know because
now the frequencies are back to
pre-covet levels
uh you know people are using their cars
as much as in the past
so we clearly need to see some price
corrections in the
in the in the business and from our
perspective what we already started
doing this quarter
is actually start pushing the system on
some price increases
uh and you know we are hopefully hopeful
that the market will also move with us
uh because at this level on an
incremental basis the business
is under severe pressure uh so i hope
that uh you know
answers your uh second i i was largely
referring to motor tp the last resource
being
i'm talking about motor od i was
referring to motorola
i'm sorry but my question was more
or not because because uh they just
wanted to understand
is it easy because of the reserve
reviews or is it because of low plane
intimidation
uh because because they usually used to
operate in the range of eighties
and maybe before in five eighteen kind
of periods around ninety
a so this 65 66 percentage kind of a
number
is more sustainable number or or we are
still we are seeing the reserve release
benefit or low claim information benefit
and that's why we are seeing this kind
of a very great
good set of numbers in multiple
locations so on moto tp you should look
at an annual number as we've always said
there could be periods where for a
quarter we could
you know as you know every quarter they
actually looks at the
data and takes a call on the adequacy of
results so there could be some
fluctuation on a quarterly basis you
should look at the annualized number
but to answer your question we believe
there's been definitely a positive in
terms of frequency drops we've seen that
across our portfolios we've also seen
some releases uh
you know in this quarter because of the
uh you know conservative
practices of reserving that we've had
but what we're also doing
incrementally is whenever we look at
reserving for the new book that we write
for the future
uh we create a you know again a
conservative buffer
uh you know margin for adverse deviation
as we call it
and so that practice hasn't changed we
continue to be conservative in terms of
reserving fraud
for the incremental book but we've seen
a bit of benefit on both sides
and that's what we are seeing but i
think you should wait for the whole year
number before we uh
take a full call that's on the tp side
and you have a third question on i think
on uh
in the middle right
so so on the individual part i think if
you look at uh
in general if you were to look at
particularly uh
a large part of indemnity gets sold in
the context of
the industry classification of retail
health uh there if you can clearly see
uh the industry growth in line with what
we also indicated that
obviously in the initial periods of the
covet situation there was clearly an
heightened
awareness and the need for one to have
some form of health insurance or the
other
and that's also reflective in so far as
the overall
growth for the market also so if you
look at quarter one growth of retail
health for the industry was about 24
this number if you see for quarter two
the industry growth on retail health was
almost about 43
and if you see for quarter three the
industry growth on
retail health is down to about 23 so
clearly
in some sense some of the pent up demand
that we had seen for quarter two
to some extent obviously we have seen
let's say a moderation of uh
the growth rates uh in line with what we
are also indicated saying that uh the
level of uh
uh incremental growth that we are seeing
particularly in quarter two
we will have to wait and see in terms of
its sustainability and to some extent
one has already seen uh that playing off
when you look at the overall industry
growth for
quarter three sh now in this backdrop if
you look at isis lombard's internet
growth again in the context of retail
for against the industry of 24 percent
our quarter one growth was about 25
if you look at the quarter two the
industry growth was about 42 what i had
indicated 4243 our growth rate was about
and for quarter three for us the
indemnity growth rate has been at about
so in line with the industry trend even
we are kind of experiencing
let's say a relative slowdown of the
pent-up demand that we had seen in
quarter two specific
and to that extent obviously the 17
growth will have uh
an impact in so far as both what we see
as uh
new individual growth and also the
extent of uh
renewables that one gets to see so
largely the
growth rates have been in line with what
we are saying and also in so far as the
market is concerned and just to add to
what gopal said
even if you look at the month or month
number in q3
uh for october we were higher than the
market growth in november we
relaunched the health product a complete
revamp we had talked about it in
in last quarter uh year also and that
initially took some time to stabilize in
the market because new product
training agents etc but december numbers
are you know
has picked up compared to november and
we are almost in line with the market
for december
but in aggregate over the three months
we are slightly below uh the industry so
we are reasonably hopeful that
uh you know that we should be uh
continually doing well in the
retail indemnity space
okay yeah that's it for myself thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of deepika mundra from jp morgan
please go ahead oh yes good evening sir
and
uh thanks for the opportunity a few
questions from my side um
last quarter you had mentioned you took
a price increase in health
uh i think uh your commentary indicated
that even more than only the title with
monolith stabilizing
um and you're typically guided to a 99
percent or
combine also 100 combined ratio would
you would you think that you could
finally see
a a meaningful underwriting profile
shift with the
change in writing cycles uh the second
question is on
uh yeah so deepika i think uh you are
absolutely right
i think uh the uh pnc business two
things
one you have to uh one you have to be
mindful of the fact that
uh the growth rates what you are seeing
particularly in the pnc segment of which
a large contributor happens to be the
fire part of the business
the industry has done exceedingly well
on
primarily driven by the rate change that
we had seen on two occasions in the last
12 months or so so hence to that extent
uh when you
now look at renewals that will that to
some extent happens in january 1
and predominantly bulk of the renewals
that will happen from april 1 onwards
you will have to kind of factor in for
some kind of a normalization of growth
rate
in so far as the fire segment is
concerned so that's one in so far as
revenues are concerned to your point on
the reinsurance
uh there this this is quarter four is
the period where bulk of the
uh discussion starts to happen in so far
as renewals are concerned and
hopefully towards the later part of the
quarter is where
most of our reinsurances will get
stitched in
because for us april 1 happens to be a
predominantly very large
big day for us and hence as i said in
quarter
in the later part of quarter four is
where most of the
renewals will happen in the context of
reinsurance having said that i think
what we have
what we are seeing as initial
experiences in so far as discussion with
re-insurers are concerned
uh again it's purely a function of what
kind of portfolio experience are you
exhibiting with the reinsurance partners
uh to that extent i think given that we
have been able to stay disciplined with
our overall operating outcomes of
combined within that hundred percent
threshold
we believe again in terms of renewing
the terms with reinsurers are concerned
we should not see any significant
but of course
there will obviously some element of to
some extent of
a price hardening that one would expect
but
we are not expecting any anything
significant given the portfolio
experience that
is lombard has been able to exhibit
relative to the quality of the book that
we haven't done it
and just to add to what gopal said if
you see you know january 1
uh renewals in the global market and
what's been happening in the asian
market
you know what was expected maybe five
six months back in terms of
significantly significant hardening of
reinsurance rates
that hasn't played through in asia and
even within that
the treaties that have been performing
well
haven't seen tremendous you know rate
increases so we remain reasonably
uh you know optimistic about the you
know discussion of the insurance even if
there's some
increase it may not be material coming
back to your first question deepika so
i think this is something that we've
been saying right that uh if
structurally the interest rate
uh of environment of the country comes
down and stays down
uh you know honestly we have always been
saying that we don't
believe that that may happen but if it
happens um
you know the industry will be forced to
become a lot more disciplined
on combined uh from i was referring more
to a short term
phenomenon that if you remember last
year also we were saying that motorola
prices have to increase
and then we had to get pandemic and you
know lockdown and hence there was
really no need for that but i think
again today
there is probably the same pressure that
the industry would be facing
at least we are you know taking some
lead in in trying to push
the pricing where we believe it's is a
reasonable uh
you know ask uh and we'll see how it
plays through
in this quarter we are reasonably
hopeful that we will be able to make
some uh
headway
thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of
jinjunwala from iifl please go ahead
yeah thanks for the opportunity am i
clear i mean you're not audible
okay um so a couple of questions one on
uh you know motor i think you know in
your initial remarks you were talking
about some
business acquisition related expenses
i'm sorry i missed a major part of that
um you know what exactly has happened on
the opex ratio for us given that uh
there is almost a 35 q increase in both
topics as well as uh
as well as on the commission sites we
just wanted to you know again understand
i think you were talking about the
acquisition of uh the transaction that
we announced i think but anyway you can
explain that
yeah so i think in general uh rishi what
effectively
has happened is i think you are
referring to the increase in the overall
cost so what we were indicating was
whenever growth starts to come back as
what we have seen in quarter three
uh we have been able to see an overall
gross premium growth of almost about
nine point two percent within that if
you would have seen motor growth
has been quite reasonable at almost
about fourteen percent growth
uh so whenever growth starts to come
back there is always uh
an impact of the up fronting of
acquisition cost that plays through the
pnl immediately
whereas the benefit in the form of
earned premium is something that will
play through
over the policy period and that's
evident when you look at for example
the net return premium growth rates for
quarter three
that number is about 20 so so the
benefit of that
nwp is something that will play through
as the earnings happen
however the cost is something that comes
and it's your friend
however this largely gets taken care of
so when you look at it from an absolute
number
obviously to that extent the
underwriting number will look a little
adverse
on an absolute basis but when you look
at it in the context of
the expense ratios i think
for example when you look at quarter two
i am talking about both
since you mentioned about both opex plus
commissions put together
quarter two the opex plus commission
ratios was roughly about
33.9 percent uh that number if you look
at for quarter three that number is down
to about 32.4 percent
and within that if you look at the opex
ratios the affects ratios for
quarter two was 27.3 and quarter three
that number is about 25.4
and this even if you see vis-a-vis
quarter three of last year
that number was at 24.7 i'm just talking
about optics ratios number that was 24.7
visibility 25.4 for quarter three of
this year
so hence to that extent i think from a
combined perspective
the impact of upfronting of expenses
gets taken care of
however from an absolute underwriting
outcome you then because of the up
fronting of cost
you get to see the underwriting results
to be little uh adverse
and just to add to one more point to go
about what google said you know when you
look at qoq
q3 is a very big period for uh for motor
compared to q2 right and and if you see
the growth rate for
q3 over q3 last year and growth rate of
q2 over
q2 last year we've actually had an even
higher growth in q3
so on both accounts there would be an
increase and the other point that gopal
i think made on the
opening call was the fact that uh you
know the acquisition that we
announced that cost has been uh
you know absorbed uh in the nine months
yeah that number is about 36 crores
in the p l of the nine months okay
um and so you know so it's fair to
assume that uh you know if the growth
rate numbers stabilize at the current
level then
you know operates as a percentage will
continue to drop
for the next three quarters as you know
incrementally premiums continue to get
recognized but of course
costs have already been uh incurred for
or
come through the pms that is exactly
what we say through in so far as
combined
if we slow down yes related to any
quarter whenever we slow down they'll
have an
impact you'll see that yeah okay and
secondly can you give us some quantum
you know uh taking fi 20 as a as a base
here
in terms of how much of the benefit
business uh
did we do in a cycle from italki bank
and
accordingly the impact on uh on combined
ratio maybe on an overall
entity perspective gopal you want to
answer that yeah uh so effectively i
think uh
rishi what we had indicated was as pargo
mentioned obviously
bank is a key distribution partner for
us in so far as
sourcing of businesses is concerned and
roughly if you look at the overall
contribution that the bank did
in so far as uh premiums are concerned
for fi 2020
uh roughly bank contributed uh so again
i am talking about the overall
contribution of all credit link
businesses
whether it is indemnity and benefit put
together
that number roughly constituted about
seven percent of the total
uh gross direct premium income of the
company uh that's for fi 2020
and in line with what we have been
indicating if you look at for the
current nine months
obviously uh it's driven by two factors
the even to that extent the levels of
disbursements have also been lower and
bank specifically uh also has been a
a key factor to a key factor to it
and this number of 7.1 percent that have
kind of
indicated uh that that's for the fi
2020.
if you look at for the nine month period
the contribution of uh
again the total credit linked policies
uh
uh through all channels put together
that number is about 2.9 percent of the
gross direct premium income that we have
written for the nine months so this
number issues for all the bank assurance
business ico bank and others
the 7.1 has gone to 2.9 uh and you know
within
the the you know bank and non-bank uh
bank uh only 75 75
would be bank yeah okay and one last
question on the regulatory side so
you know couple of things one is that
you know
you know the rule around claim
intimation for six months has that been
notified and when do we start expecting
that
you know to play out for the next year
or twelve months
and uh on our you know leverage and
other aspects of the
pnl and secondly there is some
recommendations about you know
introducing the new um you know premium
which is related to traffic violation
do you think that is something which
could potentially pass and pose a
upside risk i mean how does that playing
what do you think about this one the
claims i don't see it to be a big uh
impact for us because anyways you know
six months we would have we would play
most teams
uh within that time frame so we don't
see too much of an impact financially uh
for us
on the second one this is just a report
that has come from the committee
obviously there is a lot of interest
across all
policy makers in bringing down accidents
on the road and improving road safety
and one of the obvious factors is the
the way people drive
uh so you know this is something
you know for which the time had come
whether it will happen in this
in the coming year or not that's
difficult to predict it may not happen
so soon
but it will happen in due course there
will have to be a lot of
uh you know system uh in a sense
a data exchange that we'll have to do as
an industry and with the
uh you know other the police systems to
be able to do that
you know seamlessly but it will happen
in due course may not happen
uh in a matter of six months of course
but will happen in due course is our
sense
thank you so much and i think we didn't
answer your question
on the combined impact on the credit
link uh just to complete that
uh i think what we've been also saying
is that roughly about seven seven and a
half percent of our profit comes from
this
business so that has had an impact in
this quarter uh
and it has an impact over 1.3 to 1.7
percent of our
on our combined the credit linked health
business
that we write all right thank you
thank you the next question is from the
line of nades jain from investec capital
please go ahead uh thanks for the
opportunity sir
firstly if i look at the motor segment
we have gained
significant market share in nine months
and in this quarter
uh so what has proven that whether we
have gained market share in the new
segment or it's used
or with any particular two-wheeler uh
four-wheeler and uh
uh which segment we have game picture
and second figure
we are talking about that incrementally
the
so in this environment uh visit uh gain
market share and the growth department
yeah so i think there's a let me answer
the second one uh and then i'll ask
sanjeev to answer the first question
uh you know that's a very you know
excellent question this is you know in
terms of
when to grow market share um
and as you know we are traditionally uh
if i can call it counter cyclical we are
counter cyclical
and uh you know and our focus on gaining
market share in the first six months and
maybe first seven eight months was very
very high
as we speak very from the month of
december we've
turned a bit more cautious on the motor
segment again becoming
a lot more selective based on what we
believe in terms of the future loss
ratio
rather than the loss ratio that we've
seen in the last uh you know maybe
seven eight months so we are making
those adjustments absolutely correct
but sanji we want to take the first
question on where we've grown in the
you know seven eight months that we've
done but i think we uh we throw on a
quarter three number if you look at it
we would have we have grown in private
car two wheeler as well as commercial
vehicle
uh clearly our growth has been
excessively driven on
has been almost 33 percent on the
commercial vehicle side uh but that
being said the
i think that we will continue to see
where the opportunity lies and
we'll keep going in those particular
segments uh but if you see in terms of
the contribution you know
of new to the overall book we used to be
almost 33 percent there about it's
we have also gone back to our efficiency
in terms of using auto ninja which we
had uh
acquired last year in october so we have
got our retention the quality of
retention that we are able to do all of
that has gone about
in terms of driving our growth in the
previous nine
months but our approach primarily will
remain tactical
uh as to where we see an opportunity if
we see
something bordering on levels which
don't make sense at the portfolio level
for us we would feel free to you know
withdraw from it and we've done that to
some extent in some of the two willow
markets also
in the last nine months because we felt
that it was not uh
making economic sense for us as a
company to get in so we would
that's the problem overall approach that
we will drive and we felt that in
commercial vehicles there was a good
opportunity available we have gone and
grown that
yeah just to give you uh you know the
breakup of
q3 and nine months for new old q3 the
last quarter was about 33 66
for nine months was about 30 70
thank you before we take the next
question a reminder to participants to
please limit your questions to two per
participant
the next question is from the line of
pratik podar from nippon india asset
management
please go ahead yeah hi sir i just
wanted to check
uh when you talk about growth in
relation to upfront cost that was there
in the base also right so still we are
seeing that the
increase in costs are outstripping the
increase in nwp growth
and also in relation to this uh the
employee cost seems to be flat y o y so
what's going over there is that this
work from home policy puzzle digital
initiatives that's question number one
section is on question number two
question number two was i'm a bit faster
last two you know when you say that icsa
bank is focusing on core i thought core
was also about selling
uh ancillary products was to generate
roe because it's are we accretive
and does that mean that the icc bank has
also stopped selling sme products
such as fire health on the sme side and
lastly sir your thoughts on the third
party high x
uh which didn't happen in fi-21 uh will
they happen i mean
are you reasonably confident or is there
some indication that they might happen
in fact
yeah so uh let me the first question
i'll
ask gopal to answer in terms of the
accounting and the impact
and the employee cost etc operating cost
on the second
no the bank is selling all the other
products so all branch linked uh you
know indemnity policies that we sell to
retail customers the sme business
they're continuing to do that uh i think
the focus that we talked about for the
bank probably was more on the mortgage
side
and that's where these attachment
policies where the credit link policies
were sold
so that's a segment that they've said
that they want to focus on scaling that
business up
and it's probably they see it as an
opportunity at this point in time and
you know maybe coming from
low numbers in the first half so no the
sme and the other businesses are
continuing with the bank
uh you know with uh you know with
relation to
your third question um sorry i just
missed that question
my sense is that look as an industry we
we believe we deserve a tktp hype
because last year we didn't get it
uh so we are optimistic that we'll
get a hike in the coming year normally
we've always seen tp hikes every single
year so there should be there's no
reason why we shouldn't get it
this year particularly given the fact
that that last year we didn't uh
get one uh you know there will always
remain a concern about the economic
growth and whether there's any concern
on
you know price increase affecting growth
which in reality there isn't in this
case but
but on balance we remain very optimistic
that we'll get a
increase on first april
so on the first point i think
what in line with what we have been
saying um obviously
the market has also been equally uh
quite competitive and so far as
intensity is concerned and therefore to
that extent uh that will also be a
factor in so far as
uh acquisition costs are concerned uh
and which is what i kind of indicated
whenever kind of uh growth obviously
comes back to that extent you will have
to see it in the context of
what cost you are required to incur for
sourcing the business and
correspondingly what is the
loss ratio that you are exhibiting on
the overall portfolio and thereby take a
call with respect to the combined issues
that you want to operate at
and that's the reason if you look at it
from an expense ratio standpoint on a
very located on a sequential basis uh
both
operating expenses plus acquisition
costs put together
the numbers for quarter two was roughly
about 33.9 percent however this number
when you look at it for
uh quarter three uh that number is at
about 32.4 percent so obviously uh the
cost that you have incurred will get
expressed out immediately the benefit is
something that will play through over
the next
per term of the policy period uh on the
employee cost i think the costs are more
or less remained the same because we
i think clearly the focus for us is to
derive significant
efficiency based on the operating model
and the point that you made is
absolutely right obviously the operating
model is the key factor
and we have not and we are kind of
largely making additions
to people particularly in area where we
want to continue to make investments
therein otherwise in the rest of the
rest of the functions obviously we want
to kind of realize
both productivity improvement as well as
efficiencies in the overall
cost and that's the reason why you get
to see that number on a sequential basis
remaining more or less
flat thank you
the next question is from the lion of
madhukar ladda from hdfc securities
please go ahead uh kaiser thank you for
taking my question
uh so our health claim ratios are down
this quarter uh
and how should we think about this um
were there reserve releases on the
health segment as well
uh this this quarter and on the
investment portfolio can you tell us
uh what is the duration and yield of the
fixed income book
[Music]
so let me take the second question gopal
you can you could
answer the first question so in terms of
the duration the duration of the book
is increased to about 4.05 uh what we
did
during this quarter which is a slight
increase from the duration that we had
as on 30th september uh the call that we
took
in you know early part of this quarter
was uh
that the uh the
um the
short maturity papers were running at
very low credit spreads
uh and were probably overpriced so we
reduced some of the exposures there and
increased exposure in the
medium-term notes largely uh
government securities and state
development loads i mean you know we
only invest in a few states which we
like in terms of the quality
and that has turned out to be a good
trade
because you know coincidentally rba
announced an omo for sdl's later
uh so that's the move that we uh made we
still believe that you know interest
rates will
you know remain range bound at least for
uh you know couple of quarters at least
and we want to kind of be very watchful
about
uh you know positioning our book
uh appropriately at a time when our
views change
so at this point in time we just wanted
to uh you know shift the book
to slightly longer uh you know duration
because we felt that the
uh the short duration bonds were
overpriced at that point in time
and so the the average yield and then uh
would that also mean that
most of the capital gains is from equity
this quarter
no we've had a mix of uh capital gains
on as i said you know the the short
duration bonds uh some of the corporate
bonds in the short duration we
exited we had some capital gains there
because as we said we felt it was
overpriced and we shifted to uh
sdls and some g6 overall
yield we are you know it's it's ahead of
what we've kind of been talking about
that what we need
uh i don't want to give the exact number
but if you look at the realize written
on the portfolio
uh it's running at about uh uh if i
remember it's about seven point nine
percent if i remember
you can kind of
uh to your point with respect to the
health loss ratios i think if you look
at it on a year-on-year basis
obviously actually you will see an
increase from almost about 69.6 to
77.3 but uh yes you are right when you
look at it on a sequential basis you get
to see the number kind of going down in
quarter two from about 81.9 percent to
about 74.6 percent
this obviously includes uh let's say
health personal accident and travel all
put together
within this i think a large part of that
is with respect to health
that health numbers when you look at it
for quarter two the loss ratio for the
overall health book was
about 91 percent that number if you see
for quarter three
is at about 88.1 percent so in general i
think what we have seen is
in terms of the approach that we are
taking in so far as
reserving for ibnr is concerned
keeping in mind the fact that there
could be a possibility of claims that
could kind of come in the subsequent
period to that extent i think we did not
necessarily as we have indicated even in
our earlier calls
not to necessarily factor in for the
whole of the benefit in the initial
period but rather
kind of be a little conservative and see
the actual losses kind of playing
through
over the subsequent quarters and hence
when you start to see
numbers between quarters you would get
to see some kind of a reduction in the
overall loss issue numbers but honestly
as we keep saying quarters may not
necessarily be representative of
what the true experiences is because
there are multiple factors that go into
the
loss ratio numbers an ideal thing will
be to look at more on a year-on-year
basis
and ideally on an annual basis i think
that's what we would kind of largely
suggest and there
even on the health numbers you would
actually see when i gave out the numbers
for 69.6 to 77.3
that again included all the three
components of health personal accident
and travel
within that the health loss ratios
actually increased from about 83 percent
to 88
thank you we'll be able to take one last
question
we take the last question from the line
of shri shivani
from clsa india private limited please
go ahead
hi thank you for the opportunity uh so i
just wanted to check on this
um my understanding on the commission uh
absolute number
so given that the retention ratio is at
around 78.
whenever the retention ratio is high the
net commission number tends to go up
because the commission that you're
earning from
giving it to reinsurers uh sort of goes
down
is my understanding correct on this is
that also one of the factors uh pushing
up the
commission number for third party
so retention share is a function of
multiple segments particularly when you
look at most of the retail lines
i think they i mean in line with what we
have spoken whether you look at motor
for example on the aggregate portfolio
uh this year we have actually seen uh
particularly on motor own damage
until fi 2020 we had a small uh
reinsurance support beyond the five
percent obligatory on the one damage
portfolio till fi 2020
from fy 2021 even that particular
insurance support which were indicated
even at the beginning of the
year's call is something that we have
done away with and hence to that extent
you will get to see
an increase in the overall retention
numbers
so that's one and similarly i think uh
the more
you write retail businesses i think uh
in as what we have indicated even the
retail indemnity book for us has done uh
reasonably well and there that's again a
business where we kind of retain
predominantly uh 95 percent of the risk
leave aside the
five percent obligatory the one segment
where uh
over the last so many years we have
always had a reinsurance support
is with is with respect to the retail
benefit
and that in line with what we have
spoken earlier during this call
that's a segment where we have seen some
bit of challenges and so far as growth
is concerned so hence
a factor of all of this is what is
leading to
an increase in so far as retention
numbers are concerned and corresponding
to that
is where your net commission numbers
could undergo a change but that's again
purely a function of
what businesses do you write so for
example motor
quarter 3 we have kind of written we
have grown by almost 14
so that obviously will have and there
there is not so much of reinsurance
support as i explained
it will be purely an increase in
acquisition cost
and similarly on health indemnity
whatever business that we source
again will be a very high retention
portfolio
but in so far as the cost of sourcing is
concerned that effectively comes as a
part of your net commission numbers so
you have to look at it in the context of
which lines of businesses have grown
what is the retention corresponding to
each of those as i said for motor
predominantly 95
on the net health indemnity again
predominantly 95 on the net
but the cost of sourcing is something
that comes as a part of your net
commission numbers
and and just to add to what google
explains so the one retail business that
we traditionally have been reinsuring
is the discredit linked fit business
which uh this quarter has seen a
tremendous drop so
even for that uh the insurance
commission uh the
uh get has dropped
thank you thank you very much
we'll take that as the last question i
would now like to hand the conference
back to mr parker
for closing comments
all right so now just thank you everyone
it's been a
late evening call that we're doing uh
thank you for joining us
uh stay well stay safe thank you